Guide to the North American Congress on Latin America (NACLA) Records TAM.683
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
North American Congress on Latin America (NACLA) Records
circa 1940s-2003
1960-1999
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
North American Congress on Latin America
Thornton, Christy
TAM.683
9.5 Linear Feet in 7 record cartons, 1 small flat box, 1 media box, and 1 oversize folder in a shared box
The North American Congress on Latin America (NACLA) is a nonprofit organization that offers information and policy analysis on Latin America and its relationship with the United States, advocating for freedom from oppression and injustice in the region. Since its founding in 1966, NACLA's journalistic activism has brought English-language information to a variety of interested parties, including policy makers, students, and Latin Americanists. This collection consists of materials created and collected by NACLA that document the organization's policy and advocacy efforts, including memoranda, newspaper articles, photographs and other visual materials, publications produced and distributed by NACLA, and pamphlets and other ephemera collected by NACLA. The materials relate to a wide range of topics concerning radicalism concerning Latin America, with particular emphasis on guerrilla warfare, human rights, economic policy, and United States military intervention in the region. Although most Latin American countries are represented, the majority of the materials concern El Salvador, Guatemala, and Nicaragua during the countries' respective civil war years.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restriction.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Christy Thornton on bhealf of the North American Congress on Latin America (NACLA) in February 2016. The accession number associated with this gift is 2016.002.
Existence and Location of Copies
NACLA Report on the Americas is available at https://nacla.org/magazine. The magazine was published in print form from 1967 to 2015, and will begin exclusive digital publishing in 2016. A subscription is required to access its content.
Appraisal
Active records, duplicates of publications, and records with sensitive or financial information were not included as part of the collection.
Arrangement
This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received by the donor. Three distinct series of materials, based on format and content, have been identified:
Photographs, ordered alphabetically by country and further divided by topic
Publications, arranged into two subseries: Publications Created by NACLA and Publications Collected by NACLA, organized chronologically; and
Media Coverage, arranged chronologically.
Historical/Biographical Note
The North American Congress on Latin America (NACLA) is a nonprofit organization that offers information and policy analysis on Latin America and its relationship with the United States, advocating for freedom from oppression and injustice in the region. NACLA and its Report on the Americas started as a coalition of New Left student activists who wanted to educate and provide accurate information on U.S. interventionism throughout the region to their ideological compatriots, always keen to use a Latin American lens in their political analysis. Since its founding in 1966, NACLA's journalistic activism has brought English-language information to a variety of interested parties, including policy makers, students, and Latin Americanists.
The organization publishes an award-winning quarterly magazine, NACLA Report on the Americas; hosts an Internet resource center with news and information from Latin America; publishes books and anthologies for classroom and activist use; runs the Media Accuracy on Latin America initiative; oversees a grant program for young investigative journalists; and regularly produces radio content on Latin American affairs and U.S. policy.
Related Archival Materials
The North American Congress on Latin America (NACLA) Archive of Latin Americana is available on microfilm at The New School List Center Library. Call Number: Latin America Roll x (Ask Circ Desk).
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of materials created and collected by the North American Congress on Latin America (NACLA) in the late 20th century. The records document the organization's policy and advocacy efforts, and include memoranda, newspaper articles, photographs and other visual materials, publications produced and distributed by NACLA, and pamphlets and other ephemera collected by NACLA. The materials relate to a wide range of topics concerning radicalism and Latin America, with particular emphasis on guerrilla warfare, human rights, economic policy, and United States military intervention in the region. Although most Latin American countries are represented, the majority of the materials concern El Salvador, Guatemala, and Nicaragua during the countries' respective civil war years. The collection also includes materials concerning media coverage of the the organization and prominent members.
Latin America |x In mass media.; United States |x Foreign relations |z Latin America.; Latin America -- Politics and government -- 20th century.; Thornton, Christy
- Photographs
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged in alphabetical order by country (subdivisions by topics are not necessarily in alphabetical order).
  Scope and Content Note
  This series contains photographic prints, slides, negatives, and other graphic materials on individual countries in Latin America on subjects such as agriculture, economics and industry, guerrilla actions, human rights, indigenous peoples, labor policy, military actions, political demonstrations, religious issues, and women's rights. Prominent events appearing in this series include Fidel Castro's 1959 Cuban Revolution, the Sandinista movement in Nicaragua and the activities of the FSLN (Frente Sandinista de Liberación Nacional, Sandinista National Liberation Front); and the 1954 Guatamalan coup. A small amount of materials document protests and demonstrations in France, the Middle East, Asia, and the United States. Although the materials in this series date from the 1940s through the 2000s, the majority of the materials are dated from the 1960s through the 1990s.
  - Photo Archive Index, circa 1960-1999 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Impact Lists, circa 1960-1999 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Impact, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Image Works, 2001-2002 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Independent Photographers, 2000-2001 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - AP Photo, 1997-2001 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Not Used, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Argentina, circa 1960s (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Argentina: Politics, 1984-1994 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Argentina: General/Miscellaneous, 1945-1989; 1973-1989 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Argentina: Human Rights, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Argentina: Demonstrations, 1985-1992 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Argentina: Agriculture, 1966-1987 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Barbados, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Barbados: General/Miscellaneous, circa 1980s (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Belize: General/Miscellaneous, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Bolivia: Politics, 1977-1986 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Bolivia: General/Miscellaneous, 1974-1986 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Brazil: Demonstrations, 1979-1988 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Brazil: Indigenous Peoples, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Brazil: Environment, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Brazil: Military, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Brazil: Youth, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Brazil: Labor, 1978-1982 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Brazil: Economy/Industry, 1976-1984 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Brazil: Agriculture, 1966-1970 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Brazil: General/Miscellaneous, 1972-1999 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Brazil: Politics, 1984-1993 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Brazil: Religion, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Brazil, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Caribbean Maps, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Caribbean, 1971-1989 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Cartoons, circa 1960s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Central America: El Salvador, Nicaragua, Guatemala, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Chile, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Chile: Pictures General, 1982-1984 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Chile: Politics, 1979-1983 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Chile: Military, 1973-1986 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Chile: Opposition, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Chile: Human Rights, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Chile: Labor, circa 1960s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Chile: Demonstrations, 1979-1986 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Colombia, 1971-1990 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Colombia: General/Miscellaneous, 1971-1989 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Colombia: Earthquake, circa 1980s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Colombia: Politics, 1988-1990 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Colombia: Labor, 1975-1988 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Colombia: Economy/Industry, circa 1960s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Colombia: Demonstrations, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Colombia: Guerrillas, circa 1960s (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Costa Rica: Military, 1982-1985 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Costa Rica: Demonstrations, circa 1980s (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Costa Rica: Labor, circa 1980s (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Costa Rica: Economy/Industry, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Costa Rica: Politics, 1982-1987 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Cuba: Industry, circa 1960s-1980s (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Cuba: Agriculture, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Cuba: Health, circa 1960s-1980s (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Cuba: Religion, circa 1960s-1980s (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Cuba: Women, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Cuba: Demonstrations, circa 1958-1960s (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Cuba: Architecture, 1974-1989 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Cuba: Pre-Revolution, circa 1940s-1950s (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Cuba: Fidel Castro, circa 1950s-1980s (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Cuba: Military, circa 1950s-1980s (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Cuba: Sports/Recreation, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Cuba: Art Clippings, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Cuba, circa 1960s-1980s (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Cuba: Economy/Industry, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Cuba: Che Guevara, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Cuba: Politics, circa 1980s (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Cuba: General/Miscellaneous, circa 1960s-1980s (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Cuba: Arts/Culture, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Cuba: Children/Youth, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Cuba: Pictures to be Filed, circa 1950s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Dominican Republic, 1970-1971 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Dominican Republic: Children/Youth, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Dominican Republic: Demonstrations, circa 1980s (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Dominican Republic: Politics, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Dominican Republic: General/Miscellaneous, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Dominican Republic: Military, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Dominican Republic: Labor, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Dominican Republic: Agriculture, circa 1980s (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Ecuador, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Ecuador: Labor, circa 1990s (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Ecuador: Politics, circa 1970s (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Ecuador: Indigenous Peoples, circa 1970s (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Ecuador: General/Miscellaneous, circa 1970s-1990s (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Ecuador: Demonstrations, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - El Salvador: Slides 1, circa 1960s-1980s (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - El Salvador: Slides 2, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - El Salvador: Politics, circa 1980s (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - El Salvador: Refugees, 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - El Salvador: Demonstrations, circa 1980s (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - El Salvador: Religion, circa 1980s (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - El Salvador: Industry, circa 1950s-1980s (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - El Salvador: Portraits, circa 1980s (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - El Salvador: Salvadoran 1994 Elections (Steve Cagan) (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - El Salvador: Military, circa 1980s (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - El Salvador: Miscellaneous, circa 1980s (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - El Salvador: General/Miscellaneous, circa 1950s-1980s (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - El Salvador: Opposition, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - El Salvador: Human Rights, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - El Salvador: Poverty, circa 1980s (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - El Salvador: Elections/Miscellaneous, circa 1980s (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - El Salvador: Miscellaneous, circa 1980s (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - El Salvador: Refugee Camps, circa 1980s (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - El Salvador: Elections, circa 1990s (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - El Salvador: Demonstrations, circa 1980s (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - El Salvador: Section 1: Introduction, circa 1970s (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - El Salvador: Section 2: Romero, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - El Salvador: Section 3: Comadres, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - El Salvador: Escalation, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - El Salvador: Opposition: Politics, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - El Salvador: Military, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - El Salvador: Opposition: Selection Photographed, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - El Salvador: Guerrillas, circa 1980s (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - El Salvador: Children/Youth, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - El Salvador: Earthquake, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Guatemala: General, circa 1990s (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Guatemala: Religion, circa 1970s-1990s (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Guatemala: General/Miscellaneous, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Guatemala: Labor, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Guatemala: 1954 Coup Documents (Photocopy), 1997 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Guatemala: Demonstrations, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Guatemala: Military, circa 1980s-1990s (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Guatemala: Development, circa 1950s-1960s (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Guatemala: Poverty, circa 1980s (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Guatemala: Refugees, circa 1980s (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Guatemala: Agriculture, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Guatemala: Politics, circa 1980s (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Grenada: U.S. Military Presence, 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Grenada: Politics, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Grenada: Military, 1983-1985 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Grenada: Demonstrations, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Guyana, circa 1960s-1990s (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Haiti: Refugees, 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Haiti: General/Miscellanous, 1939-1994; 1980-1994 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Haiti, circa 1990s (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Haiti: Photos by Daniel Morel, circa 1990s (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Haiti, circa 1980s (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Honduras: Demonstrations, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Honduras: U.S. Military Presence, 1983-1985 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Honduras: Refugees, 1981-1984 (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Honduras: General/Miscellaneous, 1982-1985 (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Honduras, 1963-1975 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Honduras: Military, 1979-1984 (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Honduras: Poverty, 1980-1983 (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Jamaica, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Jamaica: Agriculture, 1953-1973 (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - Jamaica: Demonstrations, 1984-1986 (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - Jamaica: Economy/Industry, 1968-1989 (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - Jamaica: General/Miscellaneous, 1973-1986 (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - Jamaica: Labor, circa 1960s-1980s (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - Jamaica: Politics, 1972-1985 (Box 2, Folder 80)
  - Mexico: Economy/Industry, circa 1970s (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - Mexico, circa 1970s (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - Mexico: Elections, 1981-1995 (Box 2, Folder 83)
  - Mexico: Children/Youth, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - Mexico: Demonstrations, 1982-1995 (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - Mexico: Agriculture, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 86)
  - Mexico: Labor, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 87)
  - Mexico: General/Miscellaneous, 1970-2001; 1970-1989 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Mexico: Refugees, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Mexico: Politics, circa 1980s-1990s (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Mexico: Poverty, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Mexico: Women, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Nicaragua: General/Miscellaneous, 1978-1987 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Nicaragua: FSLN, 1975-1979 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Nicaragua: Demonstrations, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Nicaragua: Demonstrations, 1977-1983 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Nicaragua: Pre-Revolution Government, 1978-1982 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Nicaragua: Revolution, 1979-1986 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Nicaragua: FSLN, 1978-1985 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Nicaragua: Revolution, circa 1970s-1990s (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Nicaragua: Health, 1978-1983 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Nicaragua: Labor, 1978-1983 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Nicaragua: Politics, circa 1980s-1990s (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Nicaragua: Economy/Industry, 1967-1980 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Nicaragua: Arts/Culture, 1981-1985 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Nicaragua: Children/Youth, 1979-1989 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Nicaragua: Education, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Nicaragua: General/Miscellaneous, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Nicaragua: Post-Revolution Opposition, 1979-1986 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Nicaragua: Refugees, 1982-1987 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Nicaragua: Religion, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Nicaragua: Women, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - NACLA Events, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - NACLA Photos: Old Prints/Cartoons, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - NACLA Photo Information, circa 1980s (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Pamphlets, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Panama: U.S. Military Presence, 1980-1984 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Panama, circa 1970s (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Panama: Demonstrations, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Panama: Politics, circa 1980s-1990s (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Panama: General/Miscellaneous, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Panama: Economy/Industry, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Paraguay, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Paraguay: General/Miscellaneous, circa 1970s (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Peru, circa 1970s (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Peru: Guerrillas, 1989-1990 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Peru: Military, 1975-1989 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Peru: Economy/Industry, 1974-1979 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Peru: General/Miscellaneous, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Peru: Demonstrations, 1975-1985 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Peru: Women, 1976-1989 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Peru: Politics, 1929-1989; 1970-1980 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Puerto Rico: Demonstrations, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Puerto Rico: Demonstrations, 1970-1974 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Puerto Rico: General/Miscellaneous, circa 1970s (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Puerto Rico: Environment, 1973-1981 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Puerto Rico: General/Miscellaneous, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Puerto Rico: Portraits, 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Puerto Rico: Labor, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Puerto Rico: Politics, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Trinidad, 1800-1969; 1960-1969 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Uruguay, circa 1970s (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Uruguay: General/Miscellaneous, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Uruguay: Demonstrations, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Uruguay: Politics, 1971-1986 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Venezuela: Politics/Development, circa 1980s-1990s (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Venezuela, circa 1970s (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Venezuela: General/Miscellaneous, circa 1980s (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - IMF/World Bank, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - United States: Business/Industry/Multinationals, circa 1970s (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - United States: Demonstrations, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - United States: Demonstrations, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - United States: General/Miscellaneous, circa 1960s-1990s (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - United States: Government, circa 1960s-1990s (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - United States: Immigration, circa 1970s (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - United States: Indigenous Peoples, circa 1970s (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - United States: Labor/Unions, circa 1970s (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - United States: Military, circa 1970s (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - United States: Police, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - United States: Politicians, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - United States: Poverty, circa 1960s (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - United States: Military: Korea/Vietnam, circa 1950s-1970s (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - United States: Military: General, circa 1980s (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - United States: Politicians, circa 1980s (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - United States: Prison/Prisoners, 1941-1979; 1960-1979 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - United States: General, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - General: Agriculture/Agribusiness, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - General: Arts/Architecture, circa 1960s (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - General: Demonstrations, circa 1970s (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - General: Youths/Education, circa 1950s-1970s (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - General: Industry/Labor, circa 1960s-1980s (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - General: Immigration, circa 1990s (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - General: Religion, circa 1960s (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - General: Miscellaneous, circa 1960s-1990s (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - General: Poverty, circa 1960s (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - International/Non-American, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - International/Non-American: France, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - International/Non-American: Middle East and Iran, circa 1970s (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - International/Non-American: Miscellaneous, circa 1980s (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Latin America: General, circa 1970s (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - International/Non-American: Asia, circa 1960s-1980s (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Maps: Latin America, undated (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Maps: International, circa 1970s (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Maps: United States, circa 1970s (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Religion, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - United Nations, circa 1980s (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Women, circa 1980s (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Women's Rights, circa 1970s (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Francisco Delgado, 2000-2001 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Sample Photos, circa 2000s (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Eric Drooker, undated (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Beatriz Gonzalez, undated (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Photographer Samples, undated (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Miscellaneous Photos, 1979-1997 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Miscellaneous Photo Stuff, circa 2000s (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Photo Information: November 2002 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Photo Information: January/February 2003 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Photo Information: March/April 2003 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Photo Information, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Hegemony Layouts, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Photo Stuff from Margot, circa 2000s (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Duplicate Photos, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Miscellaneous Slides, undated (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Unidentified Slides: Cuba, Chile, Brazil, Ecuador, Colombia, circa 1970s (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Unidentified Slides: Art, undated (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Unidentified Slides: El Salvador and Mexico, undated (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Unidentified Slides: Photos, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Imágenes de Brasil by Jesus Carlos, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Ecuador Slides by Janet Jarman, undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - NACLA Graphics, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Unidentified Print, undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Exhibit Text on Kuntur Wachana and Celso Garrido Lecca, undated (Box Shared Tamiment MSOS007, Folder 12)
  - Unidentified Slides, circa 1960s-1990s (Box 9)
- Publications
  This series is arranged into two subseries, both of which are in chronological order.
  This series consists of publications both created and collected by NACLA. Publications created by NACLA include one-off publications that are not part of an ongoing series, compilations of articles written by NACLA staff sent to news services, and its regularly published journal, known by the following names throughout the years: the NACLA Newsletter (1966-1971), NACLA's Latin America and Empire Report (1971-1977), and NACLA Report on the Americas (1977-1991). Publications collected by NACLA include research materials such as general political guides and bibliographic information for human rights organizations.
  - Publications Created by NACLA